in andrewdavisandrewkdavis.comandrewkdavis97

ANDREW K. DAVIS

andrewkdavis@protonmail.com 115 Solar Street, Apartment 407 Syracuse, NY 13204 (315) 630-8565

US Citizen with Security Clearance

Professional Summary

I am an FPGA Engineer with 5 years of VHDL industry experience. I am looking for opportunities to accelerate my technical proficiency and growth. I have been both an individual contributor since June 2019, and I have been a team lead since October 2023. My work has been primarily with Zyng Ultrascale+ family of devices.

Education

Clarkson University Potsdam, NY

August 2015 - May 2019

GPA 3.520, Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Undergraduate Research 3D Fingerprint Scanning and Modeling

Created a prototype to photograph fingers and output 3D renders. Helped develop an algorithm in C++ to unwrap the 3D renders into nail-to-nail fingerprint rolls. Presented at the 2017 IARPA N2N Challenge in Laurel, Maryland.

Work Experience

SRC Inc Syracuse, NY

June 2019 - Present

- As team lead: oversee a team of 2-3 engineers; lead daily standups; assign bi-weekly tasking.
- As individual contributor: architecture and documentation; coding and simulation; hardware integration.
- As interview team-member: performed over 20 interviews, where I evaluate technical skill; and evaluate culture fit.

RF Front End MPSoC, XCAU15P, Team Lead

October 2023 - Present

- Lead a team of 3 engineers to design, simulate, and implement firmware targetting the FPGA.
- FPGA design for Artix Ultrascale+ RF Front End card. Matched hardware requirements to FPGA IO planning and clock management.
- Designed firmware that queues RF Control MORA messages and communicates with off-card hardware (filter shift registers, amplifiers, attentuators).
- Implemented manual clock routing for external clock source and performed post route timing analysis.

SDR RFSoC, XCZU43DR, Lead

May 2023 - September 2023

- FPGA design for Zynq Ultrascale+ AMS WB3XR2 Dual RFSoC. Matched hardware requirements to FPGA IO planning.
- Designed high level AXI4L memory map between RFSOC0 and RFSoC1. Documented the allocation of 4.25GB of user space addressable by each RFSoCs programmable logic.
- Performed initial bringup of card using TCL build scripts and Petalinux image using third party IP and Zynq US+ block design.

DAC Stimulator RFSoC, ZCU111, Individual Contributor

December 2020 - May 2022

- Integrated 10GbE with SFP PHY/MAC. An external PDW generator sent ethernet packets containing transmitscheduled pulse descriptor words. Designed message parsing logic on top of the extracted UDP data to extract the fields needed for transmit on the ZCU111 DACS.
- Designed AXI4-Lite controlled I/Q scaling. Scale factors were multiplied onto I/Q from full scale (1) down to zero.
 Polar inputs converted to complex I/Q and fed into complex multipliers against a single I/Q data stream from the transmit scheduler.

Motor Control MPSoC, ZCU106, Individual Contributor

December 2019 - November 2020

• Motor control with DAC8771 (single channel, 16bit DAC). AXI4-Lite to SPI interface. Wrote to DAC registers via SPI from Zynq US+ PS interfaced through Python. Verification with Oscilloscope.

SVD to LaTeX Python, Individual Contributor

June 2019 - November 2019

 Created SVD to LaTeX tool in Python, based off of CMSIS SVD specification. This tool generates memory-mapped documentation for AXI4-Lite regions: register, FIFO, and RAM memory styles.

Skills

- Hardware: Zynq US+ RFSoC/MPSoC, Zynq7000, Artix US+
- Software: VSCode, Git, JIRA, Perforce, Confluence, MS Visio, LATEX, Linux, Windows
- Languages: VHDL, TCL, Python (VUnit/CocoTB simulation, and integration scripting)
- Functional: Mentor, Strong Communicator, Team Player, Self Motivator, Book Reader